# ANKUSH CHAUHAN

\$\ +91-720.572.3841 | ankushchauhan2254@gmail.com | in www.linkedin.com/in/ankush-chauhan-0b5446166
Ohttps://github.com/ankushc1 | Jamshedpur, Jharkhand

# **PROFILE**

A Certified DevOps Engineer with seven years of professional experience, specializing in DevOps, release engineering, .net development and db setup. A proven track record of successfully working in large scale software engineering projects to implement complex and critical development and operational task.

# **SKILLS**

.NET Core | Angular | Ansible | ASP.Net | AWS | Azure DevOps | C# | C++ | Cmake | Cloudformation | Cobertura | Confluence | Dags | Docker | ELK | GIT | Github | Gradle | Grafana | HTML/CSS | IIS | Java | JavaScript | Jenkins | JFrog | Jira | Kafka | Kubernetes | Linux | Maven | MVC | MySQL | Nagios | Node.Js | Oracle Db | PCF | Prometheus | Python | Python | React | TargetProcess | Teamcity | Terraform | Typescript | UCD | Vagrant | Openshift | Helm Charts | Groovy | YAML

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

RedSeal August 2023 – July 2024
DevOps Engineer Remote

Using buildx builder for creating multi-arch docker image.

- · Use Helm charts for deployment.
- Setting up openshift cluster for a new client.
- · Managing Jenkins pipeline using groovy.
- Implemented Jfrog advance security feature and sbom in the pipeline.
- Maintenance activities like cleaning tenant and namespaces for our Kubernetes cluster.
- Troubleshooting build failures and debugging the root cause via build logs and understanding the gradle task.
- · Setting up infra and pipeline for new UI project.

Wells Fargo

June 2022 - July 2023

Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Senior Software Engineer
  - Creating Dotnetcore wrapper for static files which was developed in react.
  - Implementing concept like dynamic tokenization using dotnetcore framework.
  - Onboarding and setting up change script concept and deploying the dacpac to mysql db server.
  - · Using gradle build task for java based project.
  - Working on branch protection via configuration in yml.
  - Worked on node.js application to connect with other published code through .npmrc file.
  - Troubleshooting any Jenkins and other environment related issue during failure.
  - Understanding and implementing Vagrant concept.
  - Participating in young leadership program.

NICE Site Reliability Engineer Feb. 2021 – June 2022

Pune, Maharashtra

- · Worked on setting up production deployment cycle for media service team using ansible
- Worked on Grafana for monitoring the health, cpu utilization, max memory utilization for the servers.
- Indulged in setting up the SLI and SLO for different products
- Worked on AWS services for setting up the code infra for micro services
- · Exploring Kubernetes and creating clusters using Lens

## **Xpanxion - UST Global Group**

## Software Engineer

Oct. 2017 – Feb. 2021 Pune. Maharashtra

- Development of home-grown deployment tool (ASP.NET/AngularJS 2.0)
- Setting up CI/CD pipeline with Azure DevOps
- · Used Docker for containerization and administration of pods
- · Performed testing and production deployment
- Enhancement and Maintenance of home-grown deployment tool (ASP.NET/AngularJS 2.0)
- · Identifying and recommending optimization in the release process

July. 2017 – Oct. 2017 Pune, Maharashtra

#### Software Trainee

- Worked on 3-tier architecture in C-Sharp for a recruitment portal
- Creation of presentation layer using MVC
- · Creation and testing of the data access layer using LINQ
- · Creating Web Api for calculating eligibility of candidate for recruitment
- · Creating presentation and performing code walk-through to stalk holders

Jan. 2017 – April 2017 Pune, Maharashtra

## Internship

- · Went to different sessions which was mainly based on campus to commune
- Internship included 3 months training in DB, C Sharp, Agile and Java
- · Internship also included new tech and Soft skills

## CERTIFICATION

DevOps Beginners to Advanced with Project - Udemy Terraform cloud on-boarding - Hashicorp.

Certified Professional - DevOps Foundation (CP-DOF)

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

## AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

SPARK AWARD for being the best fresher PINNACLE OF EXCELLENCE for my work in release team.

## **EDUCATION**

ITER, Siksha 'O' Anusandhan University
B-Tech in Computer Science and Engineering

Aug. 2013 – May 2017 Bhubaneswar, Odisha